<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>klosterbruders tech rants</title>
    <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on klosterbruders tech rants</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:29:06 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://klosterbruder.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Not all cables are created equally</title>
      <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2020/01/not-all-cables-are-created-equally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 20:29:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2020/01/not-all-cables-are-created-equally/</guid>
      <description>After a long time of planning, I finally ordered parts for a new PC last year. Black Friday seemed the best time to order, even though there were less deals than I&amp;rsquo;d have wanted. While waiting for my orders to be shipped, I also found out the availability numbers in the shops were a bit overstated. That might be worth a rant for itself, but sometimes one should just let bygones be bygones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, old me</title>
      <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2020/01/new-year-old-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 23:40:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2020/01/new-year-old-me/</guid>
      <description>The year 2019 has gone just as 2020 came, ringing in the decade of the (hopefully) golden &amp;rsquo;20s once again (see also: XKCD 2249). All the while I realized that I have shamefully neglected the blog I started on a whim, even though actually having several topic ideas to write about. I have no excuse, I&amp;rsquo;m just lazy like that. Getting from &amp;ldquo;Oh, I could write about that!&amp;rdquo; to an actual blog post that&amp;rsquo;s not just an incoherent string of thought fragments always seems like way too much of a pain in the rear department for the precious free minutes between Youtube, random web pages and my warm bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When a mail client isn&#39;t just a mail client</title>
      <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/when-a-mail-client-isnt-just-a-mail-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 21:19:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/when-a-mail-client-isnt-just-a-mail-client/</guid>
      <description>The case of Mailspring.
Today, I was in need of a mail client for testing a server. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use my usual one, since that one is overloaded with accounts already. Installing one of the other big and well-known mail clients or -suites didn&amp;rsquo;t sound too appealing either. So I went to the search engine of my distrust, and keyed in &amp;ldquo;simple imap client linux&amp;rdquo;, in hopes of being presented with a list of small and simple IMAP mail clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More text processing for fun (and profit?)</title>
      <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/more-text-processing-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 22:44:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/more-text-processing-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>Why, hello again. My last awkward post was but a single scratch on the surface of what awk can do. With this post, I will try to add a second one.
The first example will involve a CSV file. CSV &amp;ndash; comma-separated values &amp;ndash; is a file type that presents values in a more or less tabular form, but instead of separated by spaces, they&amp;rsquo;re separated by commas. Who would&amp;rsquo;ve thought, huh?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text processing for fun (and profit?)</title>
      <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/text-processing-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 16:23:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/text-processing-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>Fasten your seatbelts, it&amp;rsquo;s going to get awkward.
awk, together with grep, sed and fellows like tr, wc or cut are standard tools for command line text processing on Linux, BSD and other Unix-based operating systems. They&amp;rsquo;re also bread-and-butter tools for sysadmins. Can&amp;rsquo;t remember which config file a certain setting was in? grep for it. Someone wants to know how many requests the web server served yesterday? wc to the rescue!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 19:39:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://klosterbruder.github.io/2019/08/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello, World!
For some years now, I thought I should start a blog. Either because everyone and their grandma has one, or because I had exactly one more or less nonsensical idea I could&amp;rsquo;ve thrown out onto the internet. Being lazy as heck was the main deterrent of actually doing it, the other one was a mindset of having to do it &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; on first try. I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure what &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; means in the context of blogging, so those attempts didn&amp;rsquo;t last much longer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
